[
    {
        "question": "The Galapagos Islands are part of which country?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Galapagos Islands are a province located in which country?",
        "answer": "Ecuador"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where in England is the Stonehenge monument located?",
        "answer": "Wiltshire"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two US states have their own timezones?",
        "answer": "Hawaii and Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which African capital city was known during colonial times as Leopoldville?",
        "answer": "Kinshasa"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest glacier in North America?",
        "answer": "Bering Glacier in Alaska holds the record as the largest glacier in North America."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the busiest airport in South America?",
        "answer": "S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many countries did Yugoslavia originally split into?",
        "answer": "Five"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many countries did Yugoslavia split into eventually?",
        "answer": "Seven"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state does the Rio Grande begin?",
        "answer": "Colorado"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which desert is located in the southeastern part of California?",
        "answer": "The Mojave desert"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state is Walla Walla County located?",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who did Leonid Brezhnev replace as the Soviet Premier.",
        "answer": "Nikita Khrushchev"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mustafa Kemal was the first President of which country",
        "answer": "Turkey"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Fort Erie located?",
        "answer": "Ontario, Canada"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the largest meteorite crater on Earth?",
        "answer": "Vredefort, South Africa -- 299 km diameter"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1980, Mount St. Helens erupted in which U.S. state, killing 57 people.",
        "answer": "Washington"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the US state Kansas?",
        "answer": "Topeka"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what Australian state would you find Parkes?",
        "answer": "New South Wales"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country do people traditionally eat at KFC for Christmas?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the USA`s first ski town located?",
        "answer": "Woodstock, Vermont"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country does `poinsettia` come from?",
        "answer": "Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "What European capital used to be called Christiania?",
        "answer": "Oslo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city is home to the neighborhood of Little Havana?",
        "answer": "Miami"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Union of the Comoros is located on the northern end of which water channel?",
        "answer": "Mozambique Channel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of the Seychelles?",
        "answer": "Victoria"
    },
    {
        "question": "Victoria is the capital of which country and archipelago located northeast of Madagascar?",
        "answer": "Seychelles"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did the Comoros gain its independence from France?",
        "answer": "1975"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did the Comoros gain its independence from France?",
        "answer": "July 6, 1975"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Benning?",
        "answer": "Georgia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The capital cities of Bismarck, Jefferson City and Pierre are located on what river?",
        "answer": "Missouri River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country features a man-made forest shaped into a guitar?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is home to `Snake Island`?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the oldest brewery in North America?",
        "answer": "Montreal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is home to the Catskill Mountains?",
        "answer": "New York"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city, located in the Sonoran desert, was once called Arizona City?",
        "answer": "Yuma"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Indiana?",
        "answer": "Indianapolis"
    },
    {
        "question": "Alcatraz Island is located in what bay?",
        "answer": "San Francisco Bay"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Hawkeye State`?",
        "answer": "Iowa"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Black Hills, home to Mount Rushmore, are located in which US state?",
        "answer": "South Dakota"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ikebana is the Japanese art of what?",
        "answer": "Flower arrangement -- This style originated around 700 AD as an offering in Buddhist temples."
    },
    {
        "question": "What country is home to an Isle of Youth?",
        "answer": "Cuba -- It was named Isla de la Juventud (Isle of Youth) in 1978 after a number of schools were built there for foreign students."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the Seven Summits is located on the equator?",
        "answer": "Mt. Kilimanjaro -- It is located in Tanzania. Climbing to the summit allows the climber to go from the dry, hot African plains to a climate equivalent of Antarctica`s."
    },
    {
        "question": "For mountain climbers, what is the `Explorers Grand Slam`?",
        "answer": "Reach Seven Summits and both poles -- The adventurer must climb the Seven Summits and reach the North and South poles. Fewer than 100 people have completed this feat."
    },
    {
        "question": "What nation`s tourism slogan used to be `The 45-Minute Country`?",
        "answer": "El Salvador -- The slogan meant tourists were no more than 45 minutes from the country`s top destinations."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the tourism slogan for the U.S.?",
        "answer": "`All within your reach`"
    },
    {
        "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Pakistan?",
        "answer": "K2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Ecuador?",
        "answer": "Chimborazo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the three colors of the flag of the United Kingdom?",
        "answer": "Red, White and Blue"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Canadian island is named after the father of Queen Victoria?",
        "answer": "Prince Edward Island"
    }
]